痛いだろう
Hurts, doesn't it?
Magi carry the pain of that Crest for their entire lives.
魔術師はその刻印の痛みを一生背負っていく
Your dad really gave you the perfect name.
坊やのお父さんはずいぶんと的確な名前をつけてくれたもんだ
Your origin lies in severing and binding, kid.
坊やの起源は「切断」と「結合」
It's a little different from destroying and regenerating.
「破壊」と「再生」とは ちいとニュアンスが違う
If you cut a thread and tie it back together, the
thickness will be different where the knot is, right?
一度切れて結び直おした糸は
結び目の部分だけ太さが変わるだろう
In that sense, it carries the meaning of irreversible change.
そんな風な不可逆の「変質」という意味合いを持ってる
"Kiritsugu", written with the characters for "cut" and "tie".
切って繋ぐと書いて 「切嗣」
そんな坊やにぴったりの礼装だ
I have the perfect Mystic Code for you.
I've powdered some of your ribs and put a bit of it in here.
君の肋骨を粉状に擂り潰して入れてある
これで撃たれた対象には坊やの起源が具現化する
Your origin will materialize in anything that this hits.
魔術回路を励起させてるところに打ち込めば
If you fire at your target with their Magic Circuits active, it will cut, then tie the circuits improperly.
魔術回路を切って でたらめに繋ぐ
まともな魔術師なら一撃だ
One shot will incapacitate almost any Mage.
You have sixty-six of them in total.
全部で六十六発 大事に使うんだね
Use them sparingly.
ナタリア 聞こえるかい もう少しだ
Natalia, can you hear me?
Just a little longer.
了解
Roger.
Natalia, now.
ナタリア 今だ
In the end...
結局のところ
After leaving the island, I spent the next several years with Natalia Kaminski, the woman who took me from there.
あの島を出て数年の歳月を 僕は
あの島から僕を連れ出したナタリア·カミンスキーの下で過ごした
That meant choosing the same path as Natalia.
それは つまりナタリアと同じ道
That is, the path of a hunter.
即ち 狩人として生きていくということを意味する
Natalia did not belong to any organization.
ナタリアは組織には属さず
She was a total freelancer, in it only for the money.
報奨金のみを目当てにした完全なフリーランスだった
The Mage's Association and the Holy Church.
魔術協会と聖堂教会
The strife between those two large
organizations kept her business booming.
この二大組織の闘争が
ナタリアの稼業を成り立たせていた
Since that day, I've witnessed many
tragedies like the one at Alimango Island.
あれから僕は
アリマゴ島で起きたような惨劇を何度も目にした
I learned that similar tragedies occurred all over the world every day.
似たような惨劇が
世界のあらゆる場所で
日常茶飯事のように繰り返されていると知った
Are you trying to become a champion of justice?
正義の味方にでもなるつもりか
Was there no meaning to it?
意味はなかったのか
I thought I killed my father to keep
more deaths like this from happening.
僕は これ以上こんな犠牲を増やさないために
父さんを殺したはずだ
Killing one man won't change anything.
そいつは一人やったくらいじゃあ
無理な相談だね
Kill every last person like this bunch in the world.
今回のような連中を世界中から全て殺しつくす
If you could do that, it might be possible.
そんなことがもしできたら
叶うかもしれんが
I was kidding. Don't take it seriously.
冗談だ 本気にするな
No matter what happens, do what you must to survive.
何があろうと手段を選ばず生き残る
That's the rule I set for myself regarding this business.
この稼業について あたしが決めた鉄則だ
No matter what happens, prioritize your life above all else.
何が起きようと 自分の命をまず最優先にする
If you try to save others but end up
dying yourself, it'd all be for naught.
他人を助けようとして自分が死んでしまったら
元も子もないからな
I know it's not possible to save everyone.
皆救えるなんて 思ってないさ
I just want to save as many as I can.
それでも僕は 一人でも多く救いたい
Do what you want.
好きにすればいい
Yet another tricky target.
こいつはまた厄介な獲物だね
Do you know him?
知ってるのかい
Odd Vorzak, a Mage.
魔術師 オッド·ボルザーク
He's a Dead Apostle that uses his bee familiars to increase his number of Ghouls.
使い魔である蜂を使役し グールを増やす死徒でね
The Mage's Association is offering a huge bounty for him.
魔術協会からも高額な賞金をかけられている
You know a lot about him.
詳しいね
He causes a lot of destruction.
とにかく被害の規模がデカイ
He completely upended the last town he visited.
以前あいつがいた町は 結局一つ丸ごとダメになった
A town...
町が
Natalia, can I have one?
ナタリア 一本もらっていいかい
君の国はいくつから吸えるんだったか
What was the legal smoking age in your country again?
I won't stop you, but they aren't good for you.
ま 止めはせんが 体にいいもんじゃないぞ
Where's he headed?
奴の行き先は
A flight from Paris to New York that leaves in four days.
四日後のパリ発ニューヨーク行き
Vorzak will be on board.
こいつにボルザークが乗る
I'll take this flight.
これにはあたしが行くよ
I missed Vorzak once.
ボルザークはあたしが一度取り逃がしている獲物でね
You've gotta clean up your own mess, right?
後始末は自分でやるのが筋だろ
So even you fail sometimes?
ナタリアでも失敗を
That's how tough he is.
それだけ手強い奴だってこった
What should I do?
僕はどうすれば
Most likely, he has allies in New York.
ニューヨークには おそらくボルザークの仲間がいるはずだ
I want you to get rid of them.
坊やにはそいつらの掃除を頼みたい
You'll fight Vorzak alone?
ボルザークは一人でやるってのかい
He can't carry his bees into the passenger cabin.
奴も客席までは 蜂を持ち込めない
No worries about missing him this time.
今回は 取り逃がす心配はなさそうだね
You talk too much, kid.
口の減らん坊やだ
Kid, do you copy?
坊や 聞こえるかい
Okay, loud and clear.
オーケイ 良好だ
Good luck to both of us.
それじゃ お互いの幸運を祈るよ
That was easier than I had thought.
思ったよりあっけないもんだね
The less that's required to neutralize him, the better, Natalia.
最小限の手で仕留められるに越したことはないよ ナタリア
All right, Kiritsugu.
さて 切嗣 今客席にいる奴の死体 運び出す準備は
What about the preparations to carry
his body out of the passenger cabin?
I've secured a vehicle.
もう足は用意できてる
Now we just need a doctor to carry the sick patient out.
後は急病の乗客を運び出す お医者様がいればオーケイだ
As long as you're fine with me having no license.
無免許でよければ
Hey!
おい
ナタリア どうした
Natalia, what's wrong?
Ghouls!
グールだ
面倒な事になったね
We have a problem.
He was keeping the bees inside his own body?
自分の体内に 蜂を仕込んでいたっていうのか
Natalia, get out.
ナタリア 脱出を
How many feet above the ground am I?
何フィート上空だと思ってるんだ
Unfortunately, I didn't prepare to skydive-
あいにく スカイダイビングの準備はしちゃいない
こりゃまずい どうやらコックピットがやられてるらしい
This isn't good.
Looks like the cockpit's down.
仕方ないね
There's no other way.
Natalia, you can't...
ナタリア まさか
あたしは帰るよ
I'm going home.
I'm going home alive, carrying Vorzak's body.
必ず生きて帰る
ボルザークの死体を担いでね
For that to happen, I need to do something about this plane.
そのためにはこの飛行機をなんとかせんにゃならん
何か言うことは
Anything you want to say?
Yeah...
ああ ナタリアならできるさ
Natalia, you can do this.
That will do.
それでいい
Prepare a nice, warm bed for me, and wait.
ふかふかのベッドを用意して待ってておくれ
聞こえているかい 坊や
Can you hear me, kid?
You didn't fall asleep, did you?
寝ちまっちゃいないだろうね
Loud and clear, Natalia.
感度良好だよ ナタリア
It's a rough morning, since we've both been up all night.
お互い徹夜明けの辛い朝だね
If you had gone to sleep in a bed last night, I'd strangle you to death.
昨夜の君がベッドで安眠してたんだとしたら
後で絞め殺してやりたいよ
Now, good news and bad.
さて 良いニュースと悪いニュース
Which do you want first?
どっちから聞きたい
良い知らせから話すのがお約束だろう
Don't you always start with the good news?
Okay.
オーケイ
First, the good news.
まず喜ばしい話としちゃあ
とりあえずまあ まだ生きてる
For the moment, I'm alive.
飛行機の方も無事だ
The plane is also undamaged.
コックピットには割合い簡単に辿りつけたんだが
I managed to get to the cockpit fairly easily,
though repairing the comms array wasn't so easy.
通信器の修理 手間取っちまた
操縦の方は何とかなりそうだよ
I think I can pilot it, assuming it works similar to a Cessna.
セスナと同じ要領でいいならね
Have you contacted the control tower?
管制塔と連絡は
I have.
つけたよ
They initially thought it was some joke.
初めは悪ふざけかと疑われたけどね
They said they'll escort me courteously.
優しくエスコートしてくれるとさ
And the bad news?
で 悪い方は
I'm the only one who hasn't been bitten.
結局咬まれずに済んだのあたしだけだ
Three hundred passengers and crew.
乗員乗客三百人
They've all become Ghouls now.
残らずグールになっちまった
The cockpit door is all that separates me from an airborne horde of the dead.
コックピットから扉一枚隔てた向こう側は
既に空飛ぶ死の都ってわけ
Spooky, right?
ぞっとしないねえ
Given all that, do you think you can make it back alive?
その有様で あんた 生きて帰ってこられるのか
Well, the door's pretty tough.
まあ 扉は充分に頑丈だしね
They're scratching at it as we speak,
今もガリガリ引っかかれてるけど
ブチ破られる心配はないさ
but they won't get through.
むしろ着陸の方が不安でねぇ
It's the landing that worries me.
I don't know if I can handle something this big.
こんなデカブツ 本当にあしらいきれるもんなんだか
I'm sure you'll be able to manage it.
あんたなら やってのけるさ
きっと
Were those words of encouragement?
励ましてるつもりかい
Good to hear them.
嬉しいこったね
I can handle the landing, but what do I do with these monsters?
着陸の方は何とかするが
さて この後ろの化物達をどうするか
No need to worry about that.
それは心配しなくても
I have it all worked out, Natalia.
こっちで手を打ってあるよ ナタリア
頼もしいこった
Good to know.
Fifty minutes to the airport.
空港まであと五十分ちょっと
Too long to spend praying.
祈って過ごすには長すぎるねぇ
Kid, talk to me for a while.
坊や しばらく話し相手になっておくれ
No problem.
構わないよ
You put me in a real dilemma when you said you wanted to help me with my work.
坊やがこの稼業を手伝いたいって言い出した時にはね
ほんと頭を痛めたもんさ
どう言い聞かせようと諦めそうになかったからね
It didn't look like I could say anything to change your mind.
そんなに僕は見込みのない弟子だったのか
Did I show that little promise as a student?
No, not at all.
いや 違う 見込みがありすぎたんだよ
You had too much potential.
度を過ぎてね
Far too much...
What do you mean?
どういう意味だい
指先を心と切り離したまま動かすっていうのはね
The ability to separate your feelings as you pull the trigger takes most killers years to develop.
大概の殺し屋が 数年がかりで身につける覚悟なんだ
You had it from the start.
坊やはソレを最初から持ち合わせていた
It's a hell of a gift.
とんでもない資質だよ
でもね 素質に沿った生業を選ぶってのが
But choosing your calling based solely on your talents won't always guarantee you happiness.
必ずしも幸せなことだとは限らない
If you act only on what you should do
without heed for what you want to do,
何をしたいかを考えずに
何をすべきかだけで動くようになったらね
you're nothing more than a machine, a phenomenon.
そんなのはただの機械
ただの現象だ
It's not how a human being should live.
人の生き方とは程遠い
僕はさ
I always thought of you as a much colder person.
あんたのことをもっと冷たい人だと思ってた
What are you talking about? Am I not?
何を今更 その通りじゃないか
あたしが坊やを甘やかしたことなんて 一度でもあったかい
Have I ever pampered you, even once?
You're right.
そうだな
You've always been strict on me, and you never held back.
いつだって厳しくて 手加減抜きだった
You did everything you could to teach me.
あんた 手抜きせず本気で僕のこと仕込んでくれたよな
Normally, it's the father's job to train up a boy.
普通 男の子を鍛えるのは 父親の役目なんだけどね
Well, you know...
その なんだ
坊やの場合
In your case, I'm sort of the one who
deprived you of your chance for that.
そのチャンスを奪っちまったのは このあたしが原因みたいなものだ
Well, anyway, I did feel pretty bad about it.
まあ 何ていうか
引け目を感じないでもなかったんだろうさ
This was the only way of life I could teach you.
あたしに教えられる生き方なんて 他にはなかったからねえ
So you consider yourself my dad?
あんたは 僕の父親のつもりで
Don't confuse my gender, punk.
男女間違えるなよ 失礼な奴め
At least call me "mother".
せめて母親と言い直せ
そうだね ごめん
You're right.
I'm sorry.
I've spent a long time alone in this bloodstained business.
長い間ずっと一人で 血腥い毎日を過ごしてた
So long that I even forgot I was all alone.
自分が独りぼっちだってことさえ忘れてしまう程にね
Well...
まあ それなりに面白可笑しいモンだったよ
It's been pretty entertaining in its own way.
Having something like a family, that is.
家族みたいなのと一緒ってのは
Me too.
僕も 僕もあんたのこと まるで母親みたいに思ってた
I really did think of you as a mother.
一人じゃないのが嬉しかった
I was happy not to be alone.
Come on, Kiritsugu.
あのな 切嗣
Quit saying stuff that'll embarrass us the next time we see each other.
次に会う時に気恥ずかしくなるようなことを
そう続けざまに言うのはやめろ
Geez...
ああもう 調子が狂うねえ
You're throwing me off.
I land in twenty minutes or so.
あと二十分かそこらで着陸だってのに
If I screw up when the time comes because
I'm laughing over old memories, I'll end up dead.
土壇場で思い出し笑いなんぞしてミスったら
死ぬんだぞ あたしは
I'm sorry.
ごめんよ 悪かった
Maybe I'm getting too old for this.
ひょっとすると
あたしもヤキが廻ったのかもしれないね
Maybe I screwed up so badly because
playing family made me lower my guard.
こんなドジを踏む羽目になったのも
いつの間にやら 家族ゴッコで気が緩んでたせいかもな
If so, it's probably about time.
だとすればもう潮時だ
引退するべきかねえ
Maybe I'll retire.
If you quit your job, what would you do then?
仕事をやめたら
あんた その後はどうするつもりだ
If I'm out of a job...
失業したら
今度こそ本当に 母親ゴッコしかやることがなくなるなあ
The only thing left for me would be to play the mother's part.
You really are...
あんたは僕の
本当の家族だ
...family to me.
見ていてくれたかい シャーレイ
Did you see that, Shirley?
今度もまた殺したよ
I killed again.
父さんと同じように殺したよ
I killed her, just like my dad.
I didn't mess up, like I did with you.
君の時みたいなヘマはしなかった
僕は大勢の人を救ったよ
I saved a lot of people.
If Natalia had landed successfully, there's
no telling how many people might've died.
ナタリアが着陸に成功してしまったら
どれだけの死人が出るか
分からない
Her sacrifice prevented that...
彼女の犠牲でそれは防げるんだ
That's why...
だから だから シャーレイ
That's why, Shirley...
I...
僕は
ふざけるな ふざけるな 馬鹿野郎
Shut up! Shut up!
You bastard!
Hey, Kerry.
ケリィはさ どんな大人になりたいの
What do you want to be when you grow up?
僕は
I...
Shizuka ni matataku hoshitachi no chiriyuku sora
静かに瞬く 星たちの散り逝く空
Twinkling quietly, the stars are scattered across the sky
僕は
I...
Todokanu inori ga ten to chi wo mitashiteta
届かぬ祈りが 天と地を満たしてた
Lost prayers fill the heavens and earth
Episode 19
Where Justice is Found
Hosoi eda ni hikaru no wa sakiwasureta mirai
細い枝に光るのは 咲き忘れた未来
Unblossomed futures gleam on the slender branches
Mada nagorioshisou ni tsubomi wo otoshita
まだ名残惜しそうに蕾を落とした
Still reluctant, I let the buds fall
Hora mou toki wa michite
ほら、もう時は満ちて
Look, the time is ripe
Minoru oukin no kajitsu
実る黄金の果実
A plump, golden fruit
Sono te de tsumitoru dake de
その手で摘み取るだけで
For simply plucking it with these hands
Sekai wa owaru kara
世界は終わるから
Will cause the world to end
Kegarenu mono to shite furu yuki no shirosa wa
穢れぬものとして降る雪の白さは
The whiteness of the falling, unblemished snow
Nukumori wo shireba kiete shimau no
温もりを知れば消えてしまうの
Will disappear once it learns of warmth
Kirei na yume dake ga anata wo kirisaita
奇麗な夢だけが貴方を切り裂いた
A beautiful dream was enough to tear you to pieces
Tsumetai hitomi no yasashisa to shinjitsu
冷たい瞳の優しさと真実
The truth and kindness behind those cold eyes
Shizuka ni matataku hoshitachi no inori no sora
静かに瞬く星たちの 祈りの空
Twinkling quietly, the stars fill the sky of prayers
Anata no sakebi de kono yume ga owaru made
貴方の叫びで この夢が終わるまで
Until your screams bring this dream to an end
お前は誰だ
Who are you?
悪い冗談にも程がある
What a bad joke.
どうだ 桜から奪ったその命
How does the life you've stolen from Sakura feel?
令呪をもって 我が傀儡に命ず
By my Command Spell, I order my puppet...
戻りましたね 昔のあなたの顔に
You look like your old self.
これは僕が始めた戦いだ
This is a battle I chose to fight.
私はね 幸せだよ
You know, I really am happy.
Next Episode
Return of the Assassin